Register of the British subject collection, 1906-2010
Hoover Institution Archives
British subject collection
1906-2010
XX755
Hoover Institution Archives
11 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 2 phonotape cassettes (5.5 linear feet)
Pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, bulletins, and clippings, relating to various aspects of twentieth-century British history and politics, and especially to the woman suffrage movement in Great Britain, British elections of 1974 and after, and the question of British policy regarding European unity.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, election campaign literature, bulletins, and clippings, relating to various aspects of twentieth-century British history and politics, and especially to the woman suffrage movement in Great Britain, British elections of 1974 and after, and the question of British policy regarding European unity.
Elections--Great Britain.; European federation.; Great Britain--History--20th century.; Great Britain--Politics and government--20th century.; Phonotapes.; Women--Suffrage--Great Britain.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1926-1994 (Box 2-7)
  Scope and Contents note
  Miscellaneous printed matter related to politics and society in Great Britain.
  - Miscellany. Bulletins, flyers, pamphlets, leaflets, and newspaper issues, l926-l982, relating to labor questions, anti-semitism, and to various aspects of political and economic conditions in Great Britain. Includes booklets of protest songs, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Economy. Magazine and newspaper issues and flyers relating to the miners' strike of, 1984 (Folder 2)
  - Elections. Party programs, position papers, newsletters, magazine and newspaper issues, leaflets, flyers, stickers
    - 1974 February (Folder 3)
    - 1979 May (Folder 4)
    - 1979 May (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - 1983 June (Folder 4-8)
    - 1983 June (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - (local), 1986 May (Folder 4)
    - 1987 June (Folder 5)
    - 1987 June (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
    - 1992 April (Folder 6-12)
  - Political parties
    - Conservative party. Brochures, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Green Party. Miscellaneous printed matter, 1989-1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Labour Party
      - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1993 (Folder 2)
      - Two anti-war leaflets, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Liberal Democrats. Miscellaneous printed matter, 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 3-8)
    - Plaid Cymru. Miscellaneous printed matter, 1993 (Folder 9)
    - Scottish National Party. Miscellaneous printed matter, 1992-1993 (Folder 10)
    - Ulster Unionist Party of Northern Ireland. Miscellaneous printed matter, relating to the political situation in Northern Ireland, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Referenda. Booklets, brochures, magazine and newspaper issues, flyers, and leaflets, relating to the referendum on the European Communities, 1973 (Folder 4)
  - Unions. Reports, minutes of meetings, newspapers issues, and leaflets, relating to the British Television Union, 1980-1983 (Folder 5)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1906-1992 (Box 1)
  Material related to woman's suffrage; 1992 elections
  - Elections-1992 April. Manifesto of the Liberal Democrats Women's rights. Scrapbook of clippings, serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, and miscellany, 1906-1913, relating to the campaign for women's suffrage (Folder 1)
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1990; 2 sound cassettes (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
  - Naming of Names by Ewan MacColl and Peggy Seeger, undated
    Commercially released folk songs.
    Economic Miracle by E. MacColl Just The Tax For Me by Trad., P. Seeger The Grocer by Trad., E. MacColl Not Going To Give It Back by John O'Connor Sellafield Child by Peggy Seeger Bring The Summer Home by P. Seeger, E. MacColl Maggie Went Green by P. Seeger Nuclear Means Jobs by E. MacColl House Hungry Blues by E. MacColl Dracumag by E. MacColl Rogue's Gallery by E. MacColl The Island by E. MacColl We Remember (Naming Of Names) by Trad., P. Seeger
    Catalog number: Cookc 036
    Access
    Use copy reference number: xx755_a_0013312
  - "Launch the Changing Tide," [sound recording], 17 November 1990
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Use copy reference number: xx755_a_0003719
    This cassette consists primarily of assorted poets reading their own work, but the context of the event is ambiguous and the reasoning behind the choice of poets unclear. No poets are identified by full name.
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Box 8-12)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu